<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roper Lab for Data in Community News</title>
    <link>https://roperdatalab.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Roper Lab for Data in Community News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 11:27:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://roperdatalab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Help us tell the stories of Nebraskans who have died of coronavirus</title>
      <link>https://roperdatalab.github.io/blog/2020/06/24/remembering-nebraksans-covid19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 11:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roperdatalab.github.io/blog/2020/06/24/remembering-nebraksans-covid19/</guid>
      <description>More than 250 Nebraskan’s have died during the pandemic, but we don’t know much about them. Every day, a health department in the state issues a press release that says a man or a woman of such and such age died.
But no more.
These people are mothers and fathers, brothers and sisters, friends, neighbors, members of our community. And we know so little about them.
In any other time, we would have memorials to the dead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we covered the pandemic&#39;s impact on traffic in Nebraska</title>
      <link>https://roperdatalab.github.io/blog/2020/06/15/how-we-covered-coronavirus-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 14:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roperdatalab.github.io/blog/2020/06/15/how-we-covered-coronavirus-traffic/</guid>
      <description>In March 2020, with campus closed along with businesses statewide, the data journalism class at UNL’s College of Journalism and Mass Communication started talking about how we could measure the impact of quarantine on daily life.
To measure the impact of the coronavirus on Nebraska, we looked for automated data collectors. One such automated data collector is the automated traffic counting stations that the data Department of Transportation uses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://roperdatalab.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roperdatalab.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Interested in working with us? Get in touch. We&amp;rsquo;ll get back with you as soon as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>https://roperdatalab.github.io/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roperdatalab.github.io/faq/</guid>
      <description>Got questions? We&amp;rsquo;ve got answers.
1. WHAT IS THE ROPER LAB FOR DATA IN COMMUNITY NEWS? We&amp;rsquo;ve just launched, so some of it is still being worked out. But at it&amp;rsquo;s heart, the Roper Lab is a place for students to get experience working on real world data journalism stories while helping Nebraska&amp;rsquo;s local media get access to the tools and possibilities of data journalism for their publications. We believe fiercely that the tools that journalists in New York and Washington DC work just as well in Ainsworth and Osceola.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>